

## Faisal Ahmed

**M**: (571) 409-8514 | **E**: mishu\_dc@yahoo.com 4200 CONALLY ST, Annandale, VA 22003

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack software developer with 12+ years of experience in web development using **C#.net**, **Asp.net MVC**, **Asp.net Web API**, **Entity Framework**, **React Js**, Web Automation using Selenium Web Driver and Cucumber. Currently looking for a full-time position as a full-stack developer in a challenging environment to utilize my skill and knowledge to the best of my abilities and contribute positively to my personal growth as well as for the growth of the organization.

### SKILLS (

- C#.net
- Asp.net MVC
- Asp.net Web API
- Entity Framework
- NHibernate
- jQuery
- React
- Angular

- Java
- Selenium WebDriver
- Cucumber
- Visual Studio
- Jira and Confluence
- Visual Studio Code
- Git

## **WORK HISTORY**

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER - II**

05/2019 to CURRENT

### **Net Esolutions Corporation | McLean, VA**

- Design and develop new features and/or maintain existing applications developed on ASP.NET MVC.
- Develop code and supporting documentation.
- Analyze business needs, develop requirements, design, develop and test custom software solutions.
- Provide technical leadership and take multiple systems and cross system integration into account when designing and developing solutions.
- Work with customers to understand and implement new requirements.

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

01/2015 to 05/2019

## DrFirst, Inc | Rockville, MD

- Projects: Electronic Prior Authorization, Patient Real Time Benefit Inquiry, Gaps in Care, Care Cost Estimator etc.
- Took the lead role in multiple UATs with Humana, Argus, United Health Group on behalf of DrFirst.
- Played the role of an acting application delivery manager for a short period of time.
- Participated in the myBenefitCheck project for Humana which was reported in Yahoo Finance in 2015
- Technology Used: C#.net, Asp.Net MVC, Web API, Entity framework, SQL Server.

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

04/2011 to 09/2014

## XpertLab BD Ltd. | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Projects: E-Commerce System, Mobile-based Order Capturing System,
 Distribution Management System etc.

- Collaborated with developers, QA, product owner and scrum master to assess requirements, prioritized needs and produced high-quality products.
- Mobile-based Order Capturing System helped one renounced pharmaceutical company to double the number of invoices on month opening.
- Developed a Payroll Management System as a POC within a week to assist the sales team to provide a demo to a client.
- Troubleshoot production issues.
- Technology Used: C#.net, Asp.Net MVC, Web API, NHibernate, SQL Server.

## **PROGRAMMER ANALYST**

12/2006 to 03/2010

### Computer Ease Ltd. | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Projects: Humane Resource Management System, Payroll Management System, Distribution Management System.
- Participated in different steps of SDLC.
- Designed and developed application based on requirements using C#.net, Asp.Net, SQL Server, SOAP Services, J2ME.
- Migrated legacy Visual Basic project To C#.net.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science | Computer Science United International University, Dhaka

2013

Bachelor of Science | Computer Science and Engineering
Ahsanullah University of Science And Technology, Dhaka

2006

# CERTIFICATIONS & EXAMS

Exam 483: Programming in C#

Exam 486: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications Exam 487: Developing Microsoft Azure and Web Services

## LINKS

Personal Profile: https://faisalahmed.us/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faisal-ahmed-se/

Git: https://github.com/mishu-dc

Leet Code: https://leetcode.com/mishu\_dc/